<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Zen Garden of InfoSec]]></title>
  <link href="http://CliffBarbier.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://CliffBarbier.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-05T14:27:04-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://CliffBarbier.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Cliff Barbier]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emergency Preparedness]]></title>
    <link href="http://CliffBarbier.github.io/blog/2015/01/21/emergency-preparedness/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-21T08:41:12-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CliffBarbier.github.io/blog/2015/01/21/emergency-preparedness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My own personal devotion to emergency preparedness cannot be overstated.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='It requires adaptation.  It invites constant re-evaluation, constant testing, and a constant push toward greater effectiveness & efficiency.'>
The attention I pay to this critical function borders on one of the true definitions of &ldquo;<dfn title="Any object or idea eliciting unquestioning reverence, respect, or devotion."><em>fetish</em></dfn>&rdquo;. Maybe that&rsquo;s because I come from the &ldquo;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hurricane_Katrina#Louisiana">Land of Katrina</a>&rdquo;. Or maybe it&rsquo;s because this subset of the business continuity field is a perfect match for me.  It requires adaptation.  It invites constant re-evaluation, constant testing, and a constant push toward greater effectiveness &amp; efficiency.
</span></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>What Is Emergency Preparedness?</h2>

<p><strong>Business continuity</strong> is an umbrella term for ensuring that an organization&rsquo;s critical business functions will continue to operate or recover to an operational state within a short time.  Not all business continuity problems start out as disasters.  Twitter&rsquo;s once-frequent Fail Whale indicated the runaway success of the service.  <a href="http://whatisfailwhale.info"><img class="left" src="http://CliffBarbier.github.io/images/Failwhale.png" width="300" title="Lifting a Dreamer by Yiying Lu" alt="A low-resolution screenshot of the Fail Whale on Twitter"></a>  But this success obviously caused problems for their critical business function, receiving and distributing 140-character messages.</p>

<p><strong>Disaster recovery</strong> is a subset of business continuity, which outlines how you recover from an incident.</p>

<p><strong>Emergency preparedness</strong> are the things you do in preparation for an emergency.  Beefing up resiliency, staging materials, and <em>creating a plan</em> are key components of this.</p>

<h2>Questions to ask</h2>

<h4>What are your critical business processes?</h4>

<p>What can you let slide and what has to get done to keep the business going?</p>

<h4>Do you know what you need in the event of an emergency?</h4>

<p>What items, personnel, &amp; skills are necessary for those processes that keep things going?</p>

<h4>Have you set those items aside?</h4>

<p>Recognizing that you&rsquo;ll need form FB-227/R-14 is useless if you don&rsquo;t allocate some to the emergency preparedness bin.  Also, your employee Susie needs to know that you consider her essential.</p>

<h4>Have you tested your plan using <mark>only those items</mark>?</h4>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Use only the items in your emergency preparedness bin for the test, then replace what was used.'>
This is a key point&hellip;  You&rsquo;ll never be able to fill out FB-227/R-14 without a pencil.  Even more important, once you use up your only copy of FB-227/R-14, are there more?  Use only the items in your emergency preparedness bin for the test, then replace what was used.
</span></p>

<h4>Are the items placed where you will need them?</h4>

<p>Designate a continuity site, somewhere that won&rsquo;t be disabled when your main site goes down.  Stash your stuff there and let everyone know that&rsquo;s where to meet after a problem.</p>

<h4>Is all of this checked? On what schedule? By whom?</h4>

<p>The checking process could be a training event in itself&ndash;if it&rsquo;s your turn to check the items this month, you should also go over immediate aftermath responsibilities &amp; be quizzed on them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Road Warrior]]></title>
    <link href="http://CliffBarbier.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/road-warrior/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-12T14:26:12-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CliffBarbier.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/road-warrior</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//embed.gettyimages.com/embed/170103570?et=_uohFEMTgkGyu4Enj50vgw&sig=1eumyBdkEJgp9bU8mdd-px8vTngLW20r03FHgZ0D8dg=" width="512" height="404" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>


<p>I am a road warrior.</p>

<p>There are many out there like me.</p>

<p>I sleep in a hotel for much of the year. A different hotel every month; every week; every night.</p>

<p>I eat in delicious restaurants that the TV shows will never find. I eat rubbery hotel eggs floating in water.</p>

<p>I travel for miles, navigating the roads, the trains, and the airports to reach my destination on time and safely.</p>

<p>I live out of my car; truck; carry-on. My daily life must fit inside 22 inches.</p>

<p>Half my meals are eaten standing up&mdash;half of those while rushing to get somewhere important to me, my boss, or my client.</p>

<p>I have watched my children grow up via webcam.</p>

<p>It is my job to meet for the first time and impress a person; a handful; a dozen; hundreds at a time.  This is difficult on 3 hours sleep.  I subsist on energy drinks, energy shots, or coffee.</p>

<p>I know more about the TSA&rsquo;s screening procedures than half of the TSA officers I come into contact with.  I want to shout, “you’re doing it wrong!”<br/>
But this is the last leg on my trip back home&hellip;</p>

<p>I am a road warrior.</p>

<p>There are many like me.</p>

<p><em>(Written between 2010 and 2014)</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
